#### VIGNESHWARAN.S

vigneshwaransvg@gmail.com ⊠

www.linkedin.com/in/vigneshwaransvg in

+91 8838861760, +9715554891513

Thiruvannamalai, India 💡



**Project Engineer- Electrical** with 7 years of experience in EPC Projects & construction management, Planning & scheduling, Detail Engineering, Drafting, Project execution & control, Cost estimation, Cost control & evaluation, Resource optimization.

Specialization in Projects execution in the field of Automation, Skid packages & (Pneumatic & Actuated Valves), with good knowledge of International Standards, codes and procedures related to STP, ETP, SWTP, RO and Oil & Gas projects.

Specialization in Projects execution in the field of design, manufacturing & testing of Skid package units related to Water treatment Plant (RO/ STP), Oil & Gas having good exposure to SABIC, SEWA & DEWA Projects.

**UAE Working Experience: 5 Years & 9 months** 

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To be involved in work where I can utilize skill and creatively involved with system that effectively contributes to the growth of organization.

### **CAREER SUMMARY**



#### **MAJOR PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN**

# 1. BWRO+EDI Skid Package- Lavvah Combined Cycle Power Plant (Year-2020-2021)

#### **Client: SEWA/ ELSEWEDY POWER**

**Project Description:** The purpose of this project is to treat potable water and supply the Layyah CCPP with Demin water & Evaporative Cooler make-up water as per specifications. Feed water to the Water treatment Plant will be potable water from the Layyah SWRO plant. The WTP comprising of BWRO units, EDI system & CIP system is designed to produce demineralized water.

Worked as Project Engineer for Boffin/ OSMOFLO

- Design, Documentation, Engineering, Testing of MCC and PLC panels,
   Control DB's hot & cold loop checks.
- FAT of Skid Package.

### 2. RO+DI Skid Package-STC-J UTILITIES PARK & PILOT PLANTS (Year- 2020-2021)

### **Client: SABIC/WISON**

**Project Description:** The purpose of this project is to produce de-ionized water from brackish feed water. The plant consists of a pre-treatment plant, 53.28 m3/day brackish water reverse osmosis (BWRO) plant and 48 m3/day of de-ionization (EDI) plant.

Worked as Project Engineer for Boffin/ OSMOFLO

- Design, Documentation, Engineering, Testing of MCC and PLC panels,
   Control DB's hot & cold loop checks.
- FAT of Skid Package.

#### 3. RO+ Skid SWRO. PILOT PLANTS (Year- 2020-2021)

## **Client: ARABIAN JAPANESE MEMBRANE LLC**

**Project Description:** The purpose of this project is to produce RO water from sea feed water. The plant consists of a pre-treatment plant, 77 m3/day brackish water reverse osmosis (BWRO) plant.

Worked as Project Engineer for Boffin/ OSMOFLO

- Design, Documentation, Engineering, Testing of MCC and PLC panels,
   Control DB's hot & cold loop checks.
- FAT of Skid Package.

# 4. Shut down & maintenance works of Irrigation Valve chamber (Year- 2019-20)

**Client: Dubai Municipality** 

Worked as Site Engineer for N.A.E.L Contracting Company

- Motorized Actuated Valves and shut down works.
- Glanding & Termination of installed Motorized Actuator Valves, Installation and testing of Local distribution panels.

# 5. <u>Metering skid package (Year - 2021)</u>

**Client: NOV** 

Worked as Production Engineer

 Documentation, Engineering, Testing of MCC and PLC panels, Control DB's hot & cold loop checks.

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES EXECUTED**

- Review and follow-up project specifications, project construction documents (SOW, IFC drawings, MS, ITP, procedures etc.).
- Verify detailed drawings and site conditions, reviewed and recommended works procedures and relevant method statements and ensure jobs performance with project Quality Assurance/ Quality Control (QA/QC) plans.
- Follow-up project standards, applicable codes and monitor construction activities to ensure compliance with project documents.
- Preparing material requisitions and reviewing suppliers drawing and data documentations to ensure compliance with respective project specification requirements.
- Assist in preparing the project work plan and time scheduling of project activities to achieve the
  desired target by preparing man power histogram/ manpower projection & S-curves against the
  project schedule.
- Designed and drafted Single Line Drawing, General Arrangement drawing for MCC & PLC Panels, P&ID's & PFD's
- Designed modifications to existing wiring arrangements.
- Plan and arrange required manpower and resources in discussion with site manager, allocate equipment/ manpower etc. for their optimum utilization.
- Coordinate with Engineering team, Procurement team, Project site constructions team,
   Consultant for project construction relevant critical issues and provide appropriate feedback to project management.
- Coordinate daily activities with client, sub-contractors, company management, Co- Engineers, Supervisors.
- Attend meeting periodically with top management and client to discuss project progress and other requirements.

- Weekly project progress meetings with the client personnel.
- Assist in contract management and contract administration that include handling variation claims/ change orders.
- Familiar with invoice claim, variation and other commercial claims.
- Raise the RFQ and make necessary biddings with Sub Contractors, Suppliers etc.
- Coordinating projects from awarding through completion and responsible for monitoring schedule and activities to achieve project success.
- Involved in technical procurement activities based upon the projects & Client requirement.
- Monitoring compliance to applicable codes, practices, QA/QC policies, performance standards and specifications.

### **KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- MS Project
- Microsoft Office (MS Excel, MS Power point, MS Word)
- ERP Software
- AutoCAD 2020

### **EDUCATIONAL PROFILE**

• B.E in Electrical & Electronics Engineering

Akshaya College of Engineering & Technology (2011- 2014), Anna University

## PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Self-motivated and proactive with a good sense of responsibility.
- Self-confident and have the ability to understand and get familiar with new atmosphere within short period.
- Hardworking, punctual and good in time management.

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Age & Date of Birth : 28 Years, 22<sup>nd</sup> May1993.

Sex : Male

Passport Number : M3131207

Place of Issue : Chennai

Date of Issue & Expire : 23/10/2014 to 22/10/2024

Nationality : Indian

Languages known : English, Hindi, Malayalam and Tamil

# **REFERENCES**

1. Renni Rajendra Babu- Project Manager, Osmoflo Dubai hub.

2. Dinesh Kumar - Project Manager, Boffin Control.

3. Prabhu - Project Manager N.A.E.L Contracting Company LLC

# **DECLARATION**

I do hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated herein above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Tiruvannamalai [VIGNESHWARAN.S]

Date: 14-12-2021